Guide to the Hatfield Aerial Surveys photographs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Hatfield Aerial Surveys photographs
1947-1979
PC0086
Hatfield Aerial Photographers
3 Linear feet (43 items)
This collection consists of aerial photographs of the Stanford University campus and lands taken by Hatfield Aerial Surveys, a firmed owned by Adrian R. Hatfield. The images date from 1947 to 1979 and are of two sizes: 18 by 22 inches and 20 by 24 inches.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Open for research.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of aerial photographs of the Stanford University campus and lands taken by Hatfield Aerial Surveys, a firmed owned by Adrian R. Hatfield. The images date from 1947 to 1979 and are of two sizes: 18 by 22 inches and 20 by 24 inches.
Access Terms
Hatfield Aerial Photographers
Collection Contents
- Aerial Photographs
  - Stanford campus, from Faculty housing area before Shopping Center and Medical Center built; Old Roble still standing, Stern under construction; ca. 1947, AP4 (Box 1)
  - Main academic campus, ca. 1950 (Chemistry Building bottom center, view over campus into faculty housing area), AP5 (Box 1)
  - Main campus emphasizing Branner, Toyon and Encina Halls; Crothers under construction; ca. 1947, AP6 (Box 1)
  - Close-up of main campus from Old Union across to Hoover Tower, showing wartime temporary buildings behind Education Bldg; ca. 1948, AP8 (Box 1)
  - View of campus overlooking golf course and Lake Lagunita; stadium in upper left corner; 1948, AP9 (Box 1)
  - Main academic campus from dry Lake Lagunita to Frost Amphitheater and oval; Stern Hall under construction; 1948, AP10 (Box 1)
  - View of campus emphasizing Lasuen, Salvatierra and Alvarado streets (Quad, Oval, and Hoover Tower also in frame); ca. 1950, AP11 (Box 1)
  - View of campus (Lagunita Court at bottom) with Palo Alto and Baylands in distance, 1947, AP12 (Box 1)
  - Ryan Labs on what is now Frenchmen's Hill, ca. 1950, AP14 (Box 1)
  - Probably Felt Lake, AP15 (Box 1)
  - Original Stanford barns and hole #1 of the golf course, 1957, AP18 (Box 1)
  - View of area now covered by shopping center and medical center; Hoover Pavilion visible and Palo Alto at top edge; pre 1957, AP22 (Box 1)
  - same as AP10, AP25 (Box 1)
  - Cubberly, Main Library, Hoover Tower, Memorial Auditorium with Encina gyms and Encina Hall on right side, AP28 (Box 1)
  - Quad and Oval with Chemistry Bldg and Hoover Tower, AP29 (Box 1)
  - Campus view from Branner & Toyon Halls to Hoover Tower, with Museum in upper right corner; Crothers Hall under construction; ca. 1947, AP30 (Box 1)
  - View from faculty housing area looking over campus toward Palo Alto, 1951, AP34 (Box 1)
  - Sand Hill Road at bottom, view across campus into hills, 1979, AP38 (Box 1)
  - View of Lou Henry Hoover House, ca. 1960, AP39 (Box 1)
  - Industrial Park area before major development; faculty housing area before Pine Hill I and II; (also in frame: College Terrace, Barron Park, hills beyond Junipero Serra), AP1 (Box 2)
  - Stanford campus, Woodside, Portola Valley, Searsville Lake, Jasper Ridge, and area that became SLAC, AP2 (Box 2)
  - Stanford campus, Palo Alto, Menlo Park, bay and environs, 1957, AP3 (Box 2)
  - Stanford campus: shopping center lower right, stadium mid left, hills at top edge, 1957, AP7 (Box 2)
  - Stanford campus in its regional setting, ca. 1955 (Menlo Park, Palo Alto, bay, and East Bay region), AP13 (Box 2)
  - View of Stanford campus overlooking Sand Hill Road, Stanford Hills subdivision and Stanford Golf Course; upper left Medical Center; ca. 1958, AP16 (Box 2)
  - View of Stanford campus overlooking golf course, stables, behavioral sciences center, 1957, AP17 (Box 2)
  - View of campus over Lake Lagunita, behavior sciences center in foreground, ca. 1963, AP19 (Box 2)
  - Stanford Shopping Center before Macy's, Hoover Pavilion, ca. 1954, AP20 (Box 2)
  - Overview of campus and northern cities, 1957, AP21 (Box 2)
  - Overview of campus, Menlo Park to Mountain View, ca 1960, AP23 (Box 2)
  - Overview of campus looking west, College Terrace to hills, ca. 1958, AP24 (Box 2)
  - Felt Lake with hills in distance, Alpine Road in lower right, ca. 1960, AP26 (Box 2)
  - View of campus from Sand Hill Road across Medical Center to near hills; Governor's Lane visible, ca. 1961, AP27 (Box 2)
  - Distant overview of campus from foothills out over the bay, 1957, AP31 (Box 2)
  - View of Stanford Linear Accelerator Center, campus, Palo Alto and bay, ca. 1962, AP32 (Box 2)
  - View of Stanford Linear Accelerator Center, campus, Palo Alto and bay, ca. 1969, AP33 (Box 2)
  - Published oblique aerial of main academic campus, 1949 [GP 12516], AP36 (Box 2)
  - Published oblique aerial of main academic campus, 1949 [GP 12517], AP37 (Box 2)
  - View from Hoover Tower (left right) across medical center and shopping center (with Macy's store) to Menlo Park, AP40 (Box 2)
  - View of shopping center (with Macy's store), Sand Hill Road, and Welsh Road area, AP41 (Box 2)
  - View from foothills looking across the bay, dish in foreground, 1976, AP42 (Box 2)
  - View of campus looking from faculty housing/College Terrace across campus to Palo Alto/Menlo Park and the bay, AP43 (Box 2)
  - Close-up aerial view of Hoover Tower, n.d., AP44 (Box 2)
  - View of main Quad area with Oval and original faculty housing area, ca. 1948, AP45 (Box 2)
  - View of stadium with Palo Alto High School visible; also shows gas station on campus at El Camino and Embarcadero, ca. 1948, AP46 (Box 2)
  - Palo Alto High School with Alma Street and part of PA neighborhood; shows airplanes parked on high school campus and gas station on Stanford campus at El Camino and Embarcadero, 1947, AP47 (Box 2)